Sunilkumar Yadav

J +91 9028027397

yadavsunilkumar998@gmail.com

Portfolio G GitHub
LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in fullstack development using PHP (Laravel), Python (Flask), and Golang. Worked on AI-based solutions, including data retrieval and chatbot automation. Skilled in cloud computing (AWS, Docker), database management, and optimizing microservices for fintech applications.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer — CreditFair Finance, Mumbai (Promoted)

April 2023 - Present

- Developed and deployed 400+ REST APIs with PHP (Laravel), Python and Golang.
- Built Al-powered data retrieval from database using langchain, ai embeddings and local LLM model.
- Developed an AI chatbot for customers & business interactions.
- Implemented AWS cloud, EC2, Lambda services to deploy modular Microservices via. CI /CD pipeline, utilized RDS and S3 to store and organize data, Auto scaling for load management.
- Integrated automated credit risk assessment models into loan processing.

PHP Web Developer — CreditFair Finance, Mumbai

Aug 2022 - April 2023

- Developed backend modules in PHP Laravel for authentication and API integrations.
- Revamped whole company's website individually using bootstrap, html, css and js
- Integrated MongoDB for whole system logging and real-time request tracking.
- Improved performance by optimizing database queries and caching mechanisms

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech), Computer Engineering Shah & Anchor Kutchhi Engineering College, Mumbai

2024 - Present

Diploma in Computer Technology

2019 - 2022

Government Polytechnic College, Pen

86%

PROJECTS

AI-Powered Data Retrieval System from DB

 Built a data retrieval system using langchain, Al embeddings, ChromaDB to get real time data extraction & presentation on any context or question with the help of local LLM model which has led to 4X faster data reporting.

Credit Fair Chatbot - Al Virtual Assistant

· Virtual assistant developed individually for admins, merchants, customers of the company to enhance usability & operability of CreditFair website. This has improved customer usability & satisfaction index by approx. 200%.

FurnishHomes

- · E-commerce website developed using Python (Flask). The site includes features such as user registration & login, product catalog, search & filter, wishlist, cart, order processing, and transaction management.
- Embedded mailing service using Mailtrap, used REST API & Firebase NoSQL database integration.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Languages: PHP, Python, GoLang, Javascript
- · Frameworks: Flask, Laravel, FastAPI
- · AI/ML: LangChain, ChromaDB, Embeddings, RAG
- · Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, ChromaDB
- · Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, REST APIs
- Cloud Services: AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda, RDS, ECS)
- DevOps Tools: Docker, Git, Postman, CI/CD Pipelines

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recognized as Best Achiever of the Month 4 times at CreditFair Finance.
- Reduced cost of AWS by 50% by optimizing more than 100 queries and 50 APIs.
- Developed an Al-powered data retrieval system for any time of data extraction and presentation.
- Built a chatbot that improved customer usability & satisfaction index by approx. 200%.